on line one
we initialize a local variable status
and it's randomly assigned to the string
awake
or the string tired
this problem asks us to write an if
statement
that returns the string be productive if
status is equal to
awake and returns the string go to sleep
otherwise
[Music]
so we'll compare status
to the string awake and if the value
referenced by status
is equal to awake this comparison will
return
true
a truthy condition means that this first
branch of our if statement will be
executed
and we need to return the string be
productive
otherwise we want to return the string
go to sleep
if our comparison of status to the
string awake returns true
line 4 will be executed otherwise
line 6 will be executed
moving forward in the problem
description we're told that we need to
assign the return value of the if
statement
to a variable and print that variable
so we can call our variable alert
and if line four of our code is executed
alert will be assigned to the string be
productive
otherwise alert will be assigned to the
string go to sleep
so let's output alert
and we'll also temporarily output the
value
of the variable status so that we can
ensure we are
outputting the correct alert depending
on the value of status
okay it looks like our code is behaving
appropriately
but if you look more closely at our if
statement
you can see that we have some needless
repetition
we want the local variable alert to be
assigned to
whatever the return value of this if
statement is
and in order to achieve that we don't
have to repeat this
variable assignment syntax in every
branch of our
if statement
we can assign alert to the return value
of our if statement
using this syntax
now whichever string is returned from
the if statement
will be assigned to the local variable
alert
and our code is still working as
expected
writing our code like this allows us to
leverage the return
value of our if statement we always want
to avoid needlessly repeating ourselves
when possible
you